const questions2 = [
  {
    question: "What was our Savior's last command to his disciples?",
    options: [
      'Help widows and orphans',
      'Love others',
      'Make disciples of all the nations and baptize them',
      'Honor the Sabbath',
    ],
    answer: 'Make disciples of all the nations and baptize them',
    scripture: 'Matt 28:19',
    theme: 'Jesus and His Disciples',
  },
  {
    question: "Of whom did our Savior say, 'I will make you fishers of men?'",
    options: [
      'Matthew, Peter, and Simeon',
      'Simeon, Peter, and Andrew',
      'James, Peter, and Andrew',
      'Thomas, Matthew, and Peter',
    ],
    answer: 'Simeon, Peter, and Andrew',
    scripture: 'Mark 1:17',
    theme: 'Jesus and His Disciples',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What two distinct promises did our Savior make to his disciples when he was about to leave them?',
    options: [
      'The gift in heaven and his return',
      'The salvation of their souls and the gift of the Comforter',
      'The riches of the world and a place in heaven',
      'The gift of the Comforter and his own personal return',
    ],
    answer: 'The gift of the Comforter and his own personal return',
    scripture: 'John 12:16, 19, 22, 28',
    theme: 'Jesus and His Disciples',
  },
  {
    question: 'Which apostle told Christ he had left all to follow him?',
    options: ['Matthew', 'James', 'John', 'Peter'],
    answer: 'Peter',
    scripture: 'John 13:37',
    theme: 'Jesus and His Disciples',
  },
  {
    question: 'Who took Judas’s place among the twelve?',
    options: ['Matthias', 'Stephen', 'Jude', 'Paul'],
    answer: 'Matthias',
    scripture: 'Acts 1:23',
    theme: 'Jesus and His Disciples',
  },
  {
    question: 'Which of the apostles first suffered martyrdom?',
    options: ['Andrew', 'Thomas', 'James', 'Paul'],
    answer: 'James',
    scripture: 'Acts 12:2',
    theme: 'Jesus and His Disciples',
  },
  {
    question: 'What were the first words God spoke to man?',
    options: [
      'Rule the earth',
      'Fill the earth',
      'Be fruitful and multiply',
      'Love your neighbor',
    ],
    answer: 'Be fruitful and multiply',
    scripture: 'Gen 1:28',
    theme: 'Who God Is',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the meaning of Jehovah Shammah?',
    options: [
      'Jehova is there',
      'Jehova is here',
      'Jehova is near',
      'Jehova is with us',
    ],
    answer: 'Jehova is there',
    scripture: 'Ezek 48:35',
    theme: 'Who God Is',
  },
  {
    question:
      'How did God manifest his presence at the dedication of the temple?',
    options: [
      'Fire came down from heaven',
      'A cloud came from heaven',
      'Rain came from heaven',
      'A thunder came from heaven',
    ],
    answer: 'Fire came down from heaven',
    scripture: '2 Chron 7:1',
    theme: 'Who God Is',
  },
  {
    question: 'On what three occasions are we expressly told that Jesus wept?',
    options: [
      'In Gethsemane and twice in Bethlehem',
      'Over Jerusalem and twice in Nazareth',
      'At the grave of Lazarus, over Jerusalem, and in Gethsemane',
      'At the grave of Lazarus, over Jerusalem, and in Bethlehem',
    ],
    answer: 'At the grave of Lazarus, over Jerusalem, and in Gethsemane',
    scripture: 'John 11:33, Luke 19:41, Heb 5:7',
    theme: 'Who God Is',
  },
  {
    question: 'Who is called the light of the world?',
    options: ['Moses', 'Jesus', 'John', 'Abraham'],
    answer: 'Jesus',
    scripture: 'John 8:12, 12:46',
    theme: 'Who God Is',
  },
  {
    question: 'What was the first miracle performed by Christ?',
    options: [
      'Healing of the blind man',
      'Feeding of the five thousand',
      'Water turned to wine',
      'Jesus walking on water',
    ],
    answer: 'Water turned to wine',
    scripture: 'John 2:1',
    theme: 'Who God Is',
  },
  {
    question:
      'When was the Sabbath first instituted, and by whom was it observed?',
    options: [
      'By Noah, after the flood',
      'By God, after creation',
      'By Adam, in the garden of Eden',
      'By Moses, at the giving of the ten commandments',
    ],
    answer: 'By God, after creation',
    scripture: 'Gen 2:2-3',
    theme: 'Fruit of Faith',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Who made the first confession to the Lord, as recorded in the Bible?',
    options: ['Abram', 'Jacob', 'Adam', 'Moses'],
    answer: 'Jacob',
    scripture: 'Gen 32:9',
    theme: 'Fruit of Faith',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Who delivered Israel by killing 600 Philistines with an ox goad?',
    options: ['David', 'Jonathan', 'Shamgar', 'Samson'],
    answer: 'Shamgar',
    scripture: 'Judg 3:31',
    theme: 'Fruit of Faith',
  },
  {
    question: 'Who was the first recorded person raised from death to life?',
    options: ['Tabitha', 'Jesus', 'Lazarus', "The son of Zarephath's daughter"],
    answer: "The son of Zarephath's daughter",
    scripture: '1 Kings 17:21',
    theme: 'Fruit of Faith',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Who partook of a meal prepared by an angel, and was sustained forty days and nights while in the mountain?',
    options: ['Manoah', 'Joseph', 'Elijah', 'Moses'],
    answer: 'Elijah',
    scripture: '1 Kings 19:8-9',
    theme: 'Fruit of Faith',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the whole duty of man, according to the Scriptures?',
    options: [
      'Be fruitful and multiply',
      'Love enemies',
      'Take care of the earth',
      'Fear God and keep his commandments',
    ],
    answer: 'Fear God and keep his commandments',
    scripture: 'Eccl 12:13',
    theme: 'Fruit of Faith',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which three men, in different periods, stood almost alone in their godliness, among a crooked and perverse generation?',
    options: [
      'Abraham, Daniel, and Job',
      'Joseph, Jacob, and Daniel',
      'Jacob, Noah, and Joseph',
      'Noah, Daniel, and Job',
    ],
    answer: 'Noah, Daniel, and Job',
    scripture: 'Ezek 14:14',
    theme: 'Fruit of Faith',
  },
  {
    question: 'Who beheld a vision in the valley of dry bones?',
    options: ['Jeremiah', 'Ezekiel', 'Joseph', 'Daniel'],
    answer: 'Ezekiel',
    scripture: 'Ezek 37',
    theme: 'Fruit of Faith',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Who was compelled to bear the cross of Christ to the place of crucifixion?',
    options: ['Joseph', 'John', 'Peter', 'Simon'],
    answer: 'Simon',
    scripture: 'Mark 15:21',
    theme: 'Fruit of Faith',
  },
  {
    question: 'What woman continued in prayer day and night in the temple?',
    options: ['Drusilla', 'Mary', 'Anna', 'Lydia'],
    answer: 'Anna',
    scripture: 'Luke 2:36',
    theme: 'Fruit of Faith',
  },
  {
    question: 'Who was the first Christian martyr?',
    options: ['Stephen', 'Peter', 'John', 'Paul'],
    answer: 'Stephen',
    scripture: 'Acts 7:58',
    theme: 'Fruit of Faith',
  },
  {
    question: 'Who lost their lives for using “strange” fire?',
    options: [
      'Nadab and Abihu',
      'Jacob and Esau',
      'Ahab and Zedekiah',
      'Sisera and Barek',
    ],
    answer: 'Nadab and Abihu',
    scripture: 'Lev 9:24; 10:1-2',
    theme: 'Punishments, Consequences, and Unfortunate Events',
  },
  {
    question: 'What man of Israel was stoned for blaspheming God?',
    options: [
      'The son of Isaac',
      'Methuselah',
      'The son of Shelomith',
      'Kenan',
    ],
    answer: 'The son of Shelomith',
    scripture: 'Lev 24:10-11',
    theme: 'Punishments, Consequences, and Unfortunate Events',
  },
  {
    question: 'Which three men were swallowed alive in a pit?',
    options: [
      'Korah, Dathan, Hadad',
      'Jetur, Dathan, Abiram',
      'Korah, Dathan, Abiram',
      'Korah, Dathan, Rachab',
    ],
    answer: 'Korah, Dathan, Abiram',
    scripture: 'Num 26:9-10',
    theme: 'Punishments, Consequences, and Unfortunate Events',
  },
  {
    question: 'What tribe had no inheritance in the land of promise?',
    options: ['Reubenites', 'Levites', 'Gadites', 'Manassa'],
    answer: 'Levites',
    scripture: 'Deut 8:1; 5',
    theme: 'Punishments, Consequences, and Unfortunate Events',
  },
  {
    question: 'Who was punished with death for touching the ark of God?',
    options: ['Caleb', 'Naaman', 'Uzza', 'Obed'],
    answer: 'Uzza',
    scripture: '1 Chron 13:9-10',
    theme: 'Punishments, Consequences, and Unfortunate Events',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What woman upon the death of her son, the king of Judah, murdered her grandchildren and usurped the kingdom?',
    options: ['Jezebel', 'Rahab', 'Athaliah', 'Anna'],
    answer: 'Athaliah',
    scripture: '2 Chron 22:10',
    theme: 'Punishments, Consequences, and Unfortunate Events',
  },
  {
    question: 'What man, although warned, invited his murderer to a feast?',
    options: ['Jesse', 'Gedaliah', 'Gideon', 'Dan'],
    answer: 'Gedaliah',
    scripture: 'Jer 40:14',
    theme: 'Punishments, Consequences, and Unfortunate Events',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What city was taken by stratagem and burned, with 12,000 women and children?',
    options: ['Nineveh', 'Thessalonica', 'Ai', 'Bethel'],
    answer: 'Ai',
    scripture: 'Josh 8:5; 25',
    theme: 'Wars and Conflict',
  },
  {
    question: 'How many Philistines did Samson slay with a jaw bone?',
    options: ['1,000', '40', '666', '2,000'],
    answer: '1,000',
    scripture: 'Judg 15:15',
    theme: 'Wars and Conflict',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What warrior fought so long and desperately that his hand was stuck to the hilt of his sword?',
    options: ['Elijah', 'Jabez', 'Eleazar', 'Cush'],
    answer: 'Eleazar',
    scripture: '2 Sam 23:10',
    theme: 'Wars and Conflict',
  },
  {
    question: 'Who was in command of the largest army recorded in the Bible?',
    options: ['Zedekiah', 'Ahab', 'Asa', 'Amon'],
    answer: 'Asa',
    scripture: '2 Chron 14:9',
    theme: 'Wars and Conflict',
  },
  {
    question:
      'To whom did God promise that his children should be in numbers as the stars in heaven?',
    options: ['Abraham', 'Jacob', 'Moses', 'Jethro'],
    answer: 'Abraham',
    scripture: 'Gen 15:5',
    theme: 'Promise and Privilege',
  },
  {
    question:
      "Of which person who was not of Abraham's seed did God say, 'I will make him a great nation?'",
    options: ['Zelophehad', 'Ishmael', 'Esau', 'Caleb'],
    answer: 'Ishmael',
    scripture: 'Gen 17:20',
    theme: 'Promise and Privilege',
  },
  {
    question: 'What were the three major promises God gave to Abraham?',
    options: [
      'Wealth, blessing, and the stars of heaven',
      'Seed, land, and blessing',
      'Blessing, health, and birthright',
      'Priesthood, wealth, and health',
    ],
    answer: 'Seed, land, and blessing',
    scripture: 'Gen 12:1-3; 15:5-7; 17:2-8',
    theme: 'Promise and Privilege',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What was the garden of Eden guarded with to prevent future access to the tree of life?',
    options: [
      'A pillar of fire',
      'A cherubim and a flaming sword',
      'A giant wall',
      'Leviathan',
    ],
    answer: 'A cherubim and a flaming sword',
    scripture: 'Gen 3:24',
    theme: 'Fun Facts',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the first city mentioned in the Bible?',
    options: ['Babylon', 'Nineveh', 'Enoch', 'Sodom'],
    answer: 'Enoch',
    scripture: 'Gen 4:17',
    theme: 'Fun Facts',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the name of the city to which Lot escaped at the destruction of Sodom?',
    options: ['Golon', 'Zoar', 'Silo', 'Cabul'],
    answer: 'Zoar',
    scripture: 'Gen 19:23',
    theme: 'Fun Facts',
  },
  {
    question: 'How many cities were given to the Levites for their use?',
    options: ['56', '48', '34', '99'],
    answer: '48',
    scripture: 'Josh 21:11',
    theme: 'Fun Facts',
  },
  {
    question: 'Which two men hid in a well to save their lives?',
    options: [
      'Jonathan and Ahimaaz',
      'Gideon and Phurah',
      'Saul and Jonathan',
      'David and Jonathan',
    ],
    answer: 'Jonathan and Ahimaaz',
    scripture: '2 Sam 17:17-19',
    theme: 'Fun Facts',
  },
  {
    question:
      "What queen of Bible times is described by the epithet 'that wicked woman'?",
    options: ['Lydia', 'Esther', 'Athaliah', 'Jezebel'],
    answer: 'Athaliah',
    scripture: '2 Chron 24:7',
    theme: 'Fun Facts',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What book of the Bible was written without explicitly mentioning the name of God?',
    options: ['Songs of Solomon', 'Esther', 'Ruth', 'Haggai'],
    answer: 'Esther',
    scripture: 'Esther',
    theme: 'Fun Facts',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What other nation besides Israel is to be scattered to every people?',
    options: ['Egypt', 'Lebanon', 'Syria', 'Elam'],
    answer: 'Elam',
    scripture: 'Jer 49:36',
    theme: 'Fun Facts',
  },
  {
    question: 'Who was the first Christian convert in Europe?',
    options: ['Lydia', 'Phoebe', 'Priscilla', 'Salome'],
    answer: 'Lydia',
    scripture: 'Acts 16:14',
    theme: 'Fun Facts',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Where will the great feast of the marriage supper of the Lamb be spread?',
    options: ['Earth', 'Garden of Eden', 'Bosom of Abraham', 'Heaven'],
    answer: 'Heaven',
    scripture: 'Rev 12:9',
    theme: 'Fun Facts',
  },
];

export default questions2;
